Oh!
Huh?
Greg?
Did you fetch for me the Golden comb?
Will that work?
This is a honeycomb.
Golden comb of honey, yee-he-he-he.
Greg! Oh!
Oh!
Gre-e-e-e-g!
Huh?
Never mind that, Gregory.
You've brought me the first two items...
a golden comb and a spool of silver thread.
It's just spider web on a stick.
Now, I want the sun.
The sun?
Here.
Lower the sun out of the sky
and into this China cup.
Uh, well, that sounds impossible.
Anything is possible if you set your mind to it, right?
But hurry, the sun will be setting soon, and-
Hey, yeah, that's it.
♪ Duh dih-dunh ♪
♪ dunh-dunh din-dunh ♪
♪ duh din-din dunh ♪
See, that old sun's going
right down into this old cup.
You have figured it out, and I thought you might give up.
Give up? I'll never give up.
♪ Just got to wait, just got to wait. ♪
Yes, just sit there in the cold and wait.
Huh?
Ohh...
What the...
Ohh. Ohh.
Beatrice?!
Huh?! Wirt!
Beatrice!
What are you doing out here?!
I saw Greg!
What?!
I saw Greg.
He was... with someone.
This way!
Or wait. Um...
Beatrice, you should go home.
I can't ... not yet.
Not until Greg is safe.
Okay.
We should hurry.
I... I think it was that way.
Thank you, Beatrice.
Oh! Ohh...
Huh!
Here! Edelwood!
You see? This will give us some oil, won't it?
Yes, we'll keep that light of yours shining, won't we?
Come on.
Aw! You...
♪ Come wayward souls ♪
Oh!
♪ Who wander through the darkness ♪
♪ There is a light for the lost and the meek ♪
♪ Sorrow and fear ♪
♪ are easily forgotten ♪
♪ when you submit
to the soil of the Earth ♪
Woodsman, I knew you would come.
I have something for you.
Huh! Ah!
What have you done?!
Why, I've given you another edelwood.
No!
He will burn nicely in the lantern.
No! I won't do this!
You've been grinding up lost souls for years!
I didn't know!
I didn't know this is where the edelwood trees came from!
And would it have mattered?
Would you have just let your daughter's spirit burn out forever?
Feed the lantern.
No...
I suppose, after all these years,
you just don't care for her anymore.
Hold your tongue, or I'll remove it from your mouth!
Do not speak of my daughter.
She would not wish this.
Let's get you free.
Ah!
I only wish to help you, woodsman.
You need oil, or else your daughter will...
I told you to hold your tongue!
Ha! Ha! Ha! Ha!
Greg? Greg!
I thought it was this way.
A light.
A lantern.
It looks like the woodsman's.
♪ Oh Potatus ♪
- Whoa. What happened here?
- Greg!
♪ et Molassus ♪
Greg!
♪ Si Velis eis quaere a nobis ♪
Are you...
Wirt?
Oh, Greg!
Wirt, I did it!
I beat the beast.
♪ Lenes et caldi valuti catuli ♪
Aw, geez, the leaves are even growing inside of him.
No, I was just eating leaves.
I'm sorry, Wirt.
♪ Pleni cum petri dulcibus ♪
No, no, Greg.
It's my fault we ended up here.
Everything's been my fault.
I-I should have been more...
♪ Oh Potatus et Molassus ♪
No, I mean...
my rock facts rock.
- What?!
I ... I stole it, Wirt.
I stole it from Mrs. Daniel's garden.
♪ Si Velis eis quaere a nobis ♪
I'm a stealer.
And that's a rock fact.
What?! No,
Greg, that doesn't matter.
♪ Lenes et caldi valuti catuli ♪
I does matter.
You have to return it for me, okay?
No, you can give it to her yourself!
Come on,
♪ Potatus et Molassus ♪
w-we got to get...
Jason Funderberker home, right?
Jason Funderberker...
the perfect... frog name.
Greg? Greg?!
♪ Grow, tiny seed, ♪
Let's get him out of this! Come on!
Yeah. Yeah...
Come on!
It's gonna be fine, Wirt.
♪ you are called to the trees... ♪
Ohh...
Give me my lantern.
Your lantern?
No way. We need this thing.
Yeah, I'm keeping this.
I have to get Greg home.
Your brother is too weak to go home.
He will soon become part of my forest.
I won't let that happen!
Well, then...
perhaps we better make a deal.
Deal?
Ohh...
I can put his spirit in the lantern.
As long as the flame stays lit,
he will live on inside.
Take on the task of lantern bearer...
or watch your brother perish.
Come here.
Okay.
Wirt!
Wait...
That's dumb.
What?
I'm not just gonna just wander around in the woods
for the rest of my life.
I'm trying to help you.
You're not trying to help me.
You just have some weird obsession with keeping this lantern lit.
I-It's almost like...
your soul is in this lantern.
Are you ready to see true darkness?
Are yo... Ahem
Are you?
Don't! Don't!
Here, woodsman.
I've got my own problems to take care of.
This one's yours.
My brother and I are going home.
She was never in the lantern,
was she, beast?
Listen, woodsman!
Listen to me.
Wirt...
Come with us.
I... I got to go home, too.
admit to my family it's my fault they're bluebirds.
What?!
The scissors that'll make your family human again.
You had them all along?!
I-I used them to escape
Adelaide, and th-then...
Yeah, I-I was sort of mad at you.
Oh, you...
wonderful mistake of nature!
You see, woodsman?
All who perish here will become trees for the lantern.
Cut them down with your ax.
Go! Now!
No!
Stop!
Are you really ready to go back
to that empty house?
No! Woodsman!
Goodbye, Beatrice.
Goodbye, Wirt.
♪ One is a bird ♪
♪ two are the trees ♪
♪ three is the wind in the leaves ♪
HELP...
-HUH! WIRT!
- WIRT!
♪ Four are the stars ♪
♪ Five with the moon ♪
WIRT? YOU OKAY?
CAN YOU SEE ME, WIRT?
HMM. WHERE AM I?
HOSPITAL.
HOSP... ITAL?
GREG! WHERE'S GREG?!
...AND THEN...
WIRT!
I WAS TELLING THEM ABOUT THE
TIME WE ALMOST GOT...
GRAWR.
YEAH, AND YOU WERE THERE, TOO,
JASON FUNDERBERKER.
ME?
NOT YOU!
JASON FUNDERBERKER, MY FROG.
GRAWR.
OUR FROG.
OUR FROG?
NO, NOT YOUR FROG.
HEY, SO... UH...
ABOUT THIS...
YEAH, SO...
I DON'T HAVE A TAPE PLAYER, SO...
UH, YEAH.
SO MAYBE WE CAN LISTEN TO THIS...
YOU CAN LISTEN TO IT AT MY
HOUSE. YES.
MAYBE... MAYBE WE SHOULD LISTEN
TO SOME OTHER TAPES FIRST, THOUGH
AND SORT OF WORK OUR WAY TO THIS ONE.
THIS ONE IS A LITTLE BIT... UH...
I MEAN, Y-YOU CAN LISTEN TO IT...
And so the story is complete,
and everyone is
satisfied with the ending.
And so on and so forth, and yet...
over the garden wall...
♪ How the gentle wind ♪
♪ beckons through the leaves ♪
Father?
♪ as autumn colors fall ♪
♪ dancing in a swirl ♪
♪ of golden memories ♪
♪ the loveliest lies of all ♪
Honey, eat your dirt.
Mom, stop calling it dirt.
What are you gonna do about it?
turn us into bluebirds again?
Mom...
Now, eat your dirt.
♪ the loveliest lies of all. ♪